







41)

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Summary

Jump to Section

Java Developer having round 4 years of experience in cutting-edge technologies.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects

Sound knowledge of Object Oriented fundamentals.

Experience on Angular5.

Strong experience in developing web based applications using Spring Boot, Restful framework, Rest let, JDBC.

Experience on different spring modules.

Experience on ORM technologies like Hibernate, Spring JDBC.

Good in Java 1.8 features.

Knowledge on Database Technologies like Oracle, MySQL, Mongo DB, PostgreSQL.

Good understanding on Pivotal Cloud Foundry (PCF).

Good understanding on CI/CD tools like Jenkin, bamboo.

Strong experience in developing IOT Application.

Strong experience in developing complex query's, Stored Procedures, Functions.

Strong experience in No-SQL database on Mongo DB.

Well versed with popular Java IDE's Eclipse and STS.

Experienced in using Web Server like Tomcat.

Exposure to Java and J2EE design Patterns.

Adhere of oracle coding standards to give a good quality code.

Work Experience

Cognizant as Programmer Analyst Jun 2018 to Till Date

Java Developer

Spectra Force Pvt Itd. (Bridgera LLC) as Software Engineer Nov 2016 to Jun 2018

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT) in 2015

^ Back to Top

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
CoreJava	
Hibernate	
Spring	
Mongodb	
MySQL	
RESTful Services	
Reslet	
spring boot	
PIVOTAL	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH				
HINDI				
TELUGU				

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: ESHC - Specialty Data Services [Health Care] Client: Express Scripts

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Mar 2019 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Express Scripts Holding Company is an American Fortune 100 company as of 2013, the 20th largest in the United States and is the largest PBM (Pharmacy Benefit Management) organization in United States, with 2013 revenues of \$104.63 billion.

Headquartered in St. Louis, Mssouri, Express Scripts providers integrated pharmacy benefit management services including network-pharmacy claims processing, home delivery pharmacy services, specialty pharmacy benefit management through its subsidiary Accredo, benefit-design consultation; drug-utilization review, formulary management and medical and drug data analysis services to manage drug plans for health plans, self-insured employers and government agencies (both as administrator of employee benefits and public assistance programs). One of its largest clients is the United States Department of Defenses Tricare program.

Project Title: Employer Portal [Health Care] Client: Anthem Health Insurance Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Oct 2018 - Mar 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Employer Access (EA) is one of the applications to the WellPoint and it is designed to serve central and west regions. Some regions are further divided into two classifications that are large group and small group. In EA the members are enrolled into cases or groups. Each case or group has products (plans) which will be available to employees enrolled in the case or group.

Project Title: RTI Enterprise Search Client: RTI international (https://www.rti.org/) Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2017 - Mar 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: RTI international is an independent non-profit research institute spread over 25 locations around the globe. This client currently having search facility for published research articles. Our RTI Enterprise Search application provides a unified search solution backed by big-data platform to not only their research articles but also to their clients, projects and employees info.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.